<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Sai H. Vemprala</title>
    <link>//saihv.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Sai H. Vemprala</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="//saihv.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>//saihv.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//saihv.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience</title>
      <link>//saihv.github.io/exp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//saihv.github.io/exp/</guid>
      <description>Co-founder : Scaled Foundations (2023 - Present)
Building the next generation of robot intelligence. Senior Researcher : Microsoft Corporation (2019 - 2023)
Researched and developed deep learning based perception and action models for autonomous systems. Research areas included multimodal representation learning, large language models, computer vision, and reinforcement learning. Oversaw the development of large-scale ML training pipelines. Contributed to the development of AirSim, the open source robotics simulator. Research Assistant : Unmanned Systems Lab, Texas A&amp;amp;M University (2017 - 2019)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>//saihv.github.io/pubs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//saihv.github.io/pubs/</guid>
      <description>Preprints Sai Vemprala*, Rogerio Bonatti*, Arthur Bucker, Ashish Kapoor. &amp;ldquo;ChatGPT for Robotics: Design Principles and Model Abilities&amp;rdquo;. [pdf] Yue Meng, Sai Vemprala, Rogerio Bonatti, Chuchu Fan, Ashish Kapoor. &amp;ldquo;ConBaT: Control Barrier Transformer for Safe Policy Learning&amp;rdquo;. [arxiv] Rogerio Bonatti, Sai Vemprala, Shuang Ma, Felipe Frujeri, Shuhang Chen, Ashish Kapoor. &amp;ldquo;PACT: Perception-Action Causal Transformer for Autoregressive Robotics Pretraining&amp;rdquo;. [arxiv] Journal Papers Sai Vemprala, Srikanth Saripalli, &amp;ldquo;Collaborative Localization for Micro Aerial Vehicles&amp;rdquo;, IEEE Access, 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>//saihv.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//saihv.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>Large Language Models for Robotics Current robotics pipelines require specialized engineers in the loop writing code specific to each task or form factor. LLMs such as ChatGPT unlock a new robotics paradigm, allowing a (potentially non-technical) user to sit on the loop, providing high-level feedback to the large language model while monitoring the robot’s performance. In this research, we extended the capabilities of ChatGPT to robotics, and controlled multiple platforms such as robot arms, drones, and home assistant robots intuitively with language.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
