<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Sai H. Vemprala</title>
    <link>https://www.saihv.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Sai H. Vemprala</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.saihv.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.saihv.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.saihv.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.saihv.com/posts/post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.saihv.com/posts/post/</guid>
      <description>I am currently a researcher in the Autonomous Systems group at Microsoft. My areas of focus are aerial robotics, autonomous localization/planning, computer vision and machine learning.
In 2019, I received my PhD from the Texas A&amp;amp;M University, where I was part of the Unmanned Systems Lab, headed by Dr. Srikanth Saripalli. My PhD thesis was about collaborative localization and navigation for groups of vision based unmanned aerial vehicles. During my PhD years, I spent the summer of 2016 as a robotics intern in Millennium Engineering at the NASA Ames Research Center.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.saihv.com/exp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.saihv.com/exp/</guid>
      <description>Senior Researcher : Microsoft Corporation (2019 - present)
 Senior Researcher in the Autonomous Systems group of the AI &amp;amp; Research division.  Research Assistant : Unmanned Systems Lab, Texas A&amp;amp;M University (2017 - 2019)
 Primary PhD research: Collaborative localization and navigation for micro aerial vehicle swarms using vision. Developed a computer vision based cancer tumor tracking system in collaboration with Mayo Clinic Arizona. Winner of the 2018 TAMU Data Science contest: developed data-driven predictive models using neural networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://www.saihv.com/pubs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.saihv.com/pubs/</guid>
      <description>Preprints  Daniel McDuff, Yale Song, Jiyoung Lee, Vibhav Vineet, Sai Vemprala, Nicholas Gyde, Hadi Salman, Shuang Ma, Kwanghoon Sohn, Ashish Kapoor, &amp;ldquo;CausalCity: Complex Simulations with Agency for Causal Discovery and Reasoning&amp;rdquo;. [arxiv] Guillaume Leclerc, Hadi Salman, Andrew Ilyas, Sai Vemprala, Logan Engstrom, Vibhav Vineet, Kai Xiao, Pengchuan Zhang, Shibani Santurkar, Greg Yang, Ashish Kapoor, Aleksander Madry, &amp;ldquo;3DB: A Framework for Debugging Computer Vision Models&amp;rdquo;. [arxiv]  Journal Papers  Sai Vemprala, Srikanth Saripalli, &amp;ldquo;Collaborative Localization for Micro Aerial Vehicles&amp;rdquo;, IEEE Access, 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://www.saihv.com/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.saihv.com/research/</guid>
      <description>Representation Learning and Reinforcement Learning for Event Cameras Event cameras are novel vision sensors that output fast, asynchronous data about pixel changes instead of conventional frames. This presents a challenge in applying machine learning methods to event cameras, as most learning based methods rely on frame-based inputs and convolutional neural networks. In this work, we present a way to learn representations directly from asynchronous event streams. Through a PointNet styled network coupled with a variational autoencoder, we show that the context from a fast event stream can be compressed into a latent vector, and furthermore, we show that such compressed representations are also beneficial for reinforcement learning.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>